Contact

www.linkedin.com/in/nguyen-thi-thanh-tuyen-93434a74 (LinkedIn)

Top Skills

Stakeholder Engagement Problem Solving Presentations

Languages

Chinese

English

Certifications

Presentation

COACH THE COACH (ICF) PROGRAM

Sales Productivity Program/ Excellence in Solution Selling/ Negotiation Skill

Situational Leadership

Speed of Trust

Nguyen Thi Thanh Tuyen

Empowering Workforce Development/Culture Transition Partner/ Driving HR Initiatives

Ho Chi Minh City, Vietnam

Summary

Experienced Head of Human Resources with a demonstrated history of working in the chemicals industry. Skilled in Negotiation, HR Consulting, Deferred Compensation, Sales Management, and HR Policies. Strong program and project management professional with a Master of Business Administration - MBA focused in International Management Consulting from University of Applied Sciences and Arts Northwestern Switzerland FHNW.

Experience

LTP Group
HR & ESG Senior Manager
May 2024 - Present (11 months)
Ho Chi Minh City, Vietnam

This position is responsible for the strategic management of Human Resources to support the organization's goals and objectives. This includes developing HR policies, overseeing recruitment and selection, managing employee relations, ensuring compliance with labor laws and regulations and leading initiatives to promote a culture of continuous improvement, diversity, equity, and inclusion.

Connell

5 years 2 months

Regional HR Business Partner (Vietnam, Cambodia, Indonesia, Philippines) and Head of HR, Vietnam

April 2023 - May 2024 (1 year 2 months)

Vietnam

On top of current role as Head of HR & Admin in Vietnam, this new role is

a member of the regional senior leadership team who will lead & drive the business agenda for regional business. The People Agenda which is led by regional HRBP needs to be effectively in line & support the business agenda.

Head of Human Resources for Vietnam and Cambodia

April 2019 - April 2023 (4 years 1 month)

Vietnam

Acts as HR business partner to support the Vietnam & Cambodia business's short and long-term strategy. Provides HR leadership and functional support to the country organization focusing, but not limited to, activities such as hiring, compensation and benefits, rewards and recognition, talent management, development and retention, performance management, employee engagement, change management and industrial relations.

SIGNIFICANT ACHIEVMENTS:

- Culture: Embed company culture based on company values: Safety, Diversity and Inclusion, Accountability, Innovation, Customer Centricity. Building an open and safe environment based on TRUST and collaboration relationship.
- Value Selling: Improve commercial salesforce capabilities and selling mindset. Embed the RSVP (Relationship, Strategy, Value, and Process) selling concept into the commercial organization.
- Best People Development Initiative 2021 Global People Award

AkzoNobel

8 years 10 months

Country People Service Lead March 2018 - April 2019 (1 year 2 months)

Country People Service Lead (5 Business Units with around 1000 employees: Decorative Paints, Powder Coatings, Wood Coatings, Marine and Protective Coatings, Metal Coatings)

As a People Service Lead, the primary responsibility is to oversee the delivery of HR services to employees within an organization. This role focuses on ensuring that HR processes and programs are efficiently executed and that employees receive the support that need with general accountabilities associated to this role such as Leadership and Management, HR Service Delivery, Employee Lifecycle Management, Employee relation, HR Policies and Procedures, Performance Management Support, Training and Development Coordination, Data Management and Reporting, Vendor Management,

SIGNIFICANT ACHIEVMENTS:

Lead the Success Factor HR System Project successfully implemented across AkzoNobel within country

Head of HR, VN Cum ASEAN HRBP (Thailand, Indonesia, Malaysia, Vietnam) – BU Powder Coatings
July 2010 - February 2018 (7 years 8 months)

04/2014-02/2018: Human Resources Manager, Vietnam Cum ASEAN HR Business Partner (Thailand, Indonesia, Malaysia, Vietnam) – BU Powder Coatings

07/2010-03/2014: Human Resources Manager - BU Powder Coatings

As a Cluster HRBP, the primary accountability is to oversee all aspects of the HR function within an organization and shape the organization's culture, supporting its strategic objectives, and ensuring the well-being and effectiveness of the workforce included but not limited to Strategic HR Leadership, Organization Development included organizational design, change management, and culture transformation efforts to support business growth and agility, Talent Acquisition and Management, Employee Engagement and Relations, Performance Management, Learning and Development, Total Rewards, HR Analytics and Data Driven Decision making, Diversity, Equity and Inclusion, Legal and Ethics Compliance, Leadership and Talent Development, Employee Communication.

SIGNIFICANT ACHIEVMENTS

- Asia Pacific Top Performer Award (2015) APAC Award for Functional category and appointed for Global Star Program 2016-2019
- Lead & Execute the Powder School successfully and build a strong successor bench for critical positions.
- Improve Staff Turnover Rate from 35% in 2010 to the market standard around 12-15%
- Employee Engagement score was improved year on year from 3.75 points in year 2014 up to 4.15 and 4.4 based on Gallup Engagement Survey
- Successfully recruit and build the Country Leadership Team for Powder
 Coating business from forming stage to performing stage through assimilation
 and intervention program

BSI

Training cum Customer Services Manager October 2006 - July 2010 (3 years 10 months) Ho Chi Minh City

One of the first employee together with General Director set up business in Vietnam for BSI. The primary responsibilities is to oversee activities relating to internal and external training and certification services, act as a main contact

window between customers, external partners with the organization to ensure the services delivered to customer in a professional manner

SIGNIFICANT ACHIEVMENTS:

Lead and oversee all general activities of the newly set up BSI office Develop the working standard procedures and guidance regarding to Customer Service and Training function and operate smoothly.

AkzoNobel

Production Supervisor October 2003 - October 2006 (3 years 1 month)

07/2005 – 10/ 2006: Production Supervisor

10/2003-06/2005: Production Assistant

The main responsibilities are to oversee the production process to ensure efficiency, quality, and safety included but not limited to scheduling and planning, supervise production operation, Quality control, Health and Safety compliance, training and people development, problem solving and continuous improvement.

SIGNIFICANT ACHIEVMENTS:

Lead and execute actions for manufacturing and achieve the ISO 9001, ISO 14001 & OHSAS 18001 Certification; Initiate and lead the certified operation program to build the ready operation workforce.

Education

University of Applied Sciences and Arts Northwestern Switzerland FHNW

Executive MBA, International Management Consulting

UNIVERSITY OF SOCIAL SCIENCES AND HUMANITIES (USSH)
Bachelor of Arts - BA, Faculty of Oriential Studies